Guide to the Gary Indiana Papers 1976-2005 MSS.168
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IV: Flyers and Visual Materials
  - Subseries A: Flyer and Program Scrapbook
    - A Project [by] Robert Gober / Christopher Wool, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Postcard for Indiana's reading of The Sinking of the Titanic, undated (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - A Smuggler's Life by Daniel Schmid postcard, undated (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Curse of the Dog People and Phantoms of Louisiana postcard, undated (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Body Painting retrospective postcard, undated (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Non-scrapbook flyers (1982-1984 and undated) (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Subseries B: Visual Materials
    Consists of assorted visual materials, including publication artwork for several of Indiana's novels, photographs of work by Bill Rice, a calendar entitled "Men of The Bar," collage materials and miscellaneous artwork.
    - Publication artwork, undated (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - "Color Proofs for Book Jacket" [Depraved Indifference], undated (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - "Bill's Picasso Studies", undated (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Original artwork labeled "[Canal] Rotterdam", undated (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Men of The Bar calendar, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - "Collage Pieces" - Folder 1, undated (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - "Collage Pieces" - Folder 2, undated (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - "Collage Pieces" - Folder 3, undated (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - "Collage Pieces" - Folder 4, undated (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - "Collage Pieces" - Folder 5, undated (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - "Collage Pieces" - Folder 6, undated (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - "Koran Pages", undated (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Misc. Art/Collage Materials, undated (Box 3, Folder 137)
- Series V: Printed Materials
  This series consists of published materials, including books, theatre programs, and periodicals, many of which include Indiana's writing or writing about Indiana. One issue of Night (no. 52) has been moved to the Oversize series [Folder 161].
  - Other Stages #4.15, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Framework #18, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Between C and D #1.2, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - New Observations #31: "Here Come the Murgatroyds." Ed. Gary Indiana., 1985 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - City Magazine International #18. In French., 1986 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Between C and D #3.2, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Dickson, Jane. Life Under Neon., 1989 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Roy Cohn/Jack Smith theater program, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Jean Genet theater program, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Film Comment #39.1 and 41.3, 2003-2005 (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - artUS #7 and 8, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - Spunky International: Translux, undated (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - Bomb #6, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Bomb #21, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - Bomb #24, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - Bookforum (Summer 1996-Summer 2004), 1996-2004 (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - Bookforum (Oct/Nov 2004-Apr/May 2005), 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - Village Voice Vol. XLII #30 and 32, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Voice Literary Supplement (5 issues), 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - NO Magazine #2, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - London Review of Books Vol. 25 #21, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Visit #6 (Govett-Brewster Art Gallery), 2003 (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - Weekly World News, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 160)
- Series VI: Clippings
  - Subseries A: Clippings of writing by Indiana
    Consists of clippings of art criticism, essays, and other items written by Indiana. This includes substantial criticism written for the Village Voice, Artforum, and Art in America, among other publications.
    - Village Voice, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 162)
    - Village Voice (Jan-Jun 1985) (Box 5, Folder 163)
    - Village Voice (Jul-Dec 1985) (Box 5, Folder 164)
    - Village Voice (Jan-Jun 1986) (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - Village Voice (Jul-Dec 1986) (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Village Voice (Jan-Jun 1987) (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - Village Voice (Jul-Dec 1987) (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - Village Voice (1988-1989) (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - Village Voice (1990-June 1992), 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 170)
    - Village Voice (July 1992-1995) (Box 5, Folder 170A)
    - Village Voice (1996-2004) (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - Art in America (1983) (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - Art in America (1984) (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - Art in America (1985) (Box 5, Folder 174)
    - Art in America (1986 and undated) (Box 5, Folder 175)
    - Artforum (1980-1989) (Box 5, Folder 176)
    - Artforum (1990-1999) (Box 5, Folder 177)
    - Artforum (2000-2004 and undated) (Box 5, Folder 178)
    - Bookforum, 1997-2003 (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - East Village Eye, 1980-1983 (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - Bomb, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - Los Angeles Times, 1998-2005 (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - Film Comment, undated (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - Valie Export writing, undated (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - Misc. Publications (1980-1989) (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - Misc. Publications (1990-1999) (Box 5, Folder 186)
    - Misc. Publications (2000-2005) (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - Misc. Publications (undated) (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - Subseries B: Clippings of reviews and writing about Indiana
    Consists of clippings of writing about Indiana or reviews of his published works.
    - Theater and Performance Reviews, 1979-1992 (Box 6, Folder 189)
    - Horse Crazy reviews, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 190)
    - Gone Tomorrow reviews, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 191)
    - Rent Boy reviews, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - Let It Bleed reviews, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - Resentment reviews (May-Aug. 15, 1997) (Box 6, Folder 194)
    - Resentment reviews (Aug. 15, 1997-1998) (Box 6, Folder 195)
    - Three Month Fever reviews, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 196)
    - Depraved Indifference reviews, 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 197)
    - Do Everything In The Dark reviews, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 198)
    - The Schwarzenegger Syndrome reviews, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 199)
    - Grouped Gone Tomorrow/Rent Boy reviews, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 200)
    - Grouped Rent Boy/Horse Crazy/Gone Tomorrow reviews, 1989-1994 (Box 6, Folder 201)
    - "Rent Boy reviews", 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 202)
    - Misc. Mentions of Indiana, 1979-1993 (Box 6, Folder 203)
  - Subseries C: Clippings of Research Materials
    consists of clippings used as research materials, including those regarding Henri Cartier-Bresson, Witold Gombrowicz, and Valie Export, among others.
    - Valie Export materials, 1977-1994 (Box 6, Folder 204)
    - Henri Cartier-Bresson materials, 2001-2005 (Box 6, Folder 205)
    - Witold Gombrowicz materials, 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 206)
    - Thomas Beer materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 207)
    - "Mazes", 2001-2005 (Box 6, Folder 208)
    - NY Times Versace memorial article, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 209)
    - Misc. Publications and Articles (1984-2004 and undated) (Box 6, Folder 210)
    - Misc. Research Clippings (1999-2005 and undated) (Box 6, Folder 211)
- Series VII: Photography and Snapshots
  - Subseries A: 4 x 5" snapshots
    Contains Indiana's 4 x 5 snapshots, including documentation of the Toronto Film Festival premiere of David Cronenberg's Naked Lunch, The Dazzling 1987 New York Flower Show, trips to Latin America, downtown New York City street scenes, and a New York gallery opening and party. Also included are evidence photos from the Andrew Cunanan case, the basis for Indiana's novel Three Month Fever.
    - Naked Lunch and "Dennis Cooper in Toronto", undated (Box 7, Folder no number)
    - Andrew Cunanan evidence photos, undated (Box 7, Folder no number)
    - Gallery opening and party snapshots, undated (Box 7, Folder no number)
    - Downtown New York, undated (Box 8, Folder no number)
    - The Dazzling 1987 New York Flower Show, undated (Box 8, Folder no number)
    - Latin America, undated (Box 8, Folder no number)
    - New York skyline, undated (Box 8, Folder no number)
    - Black and white New York City photos, undated (Box 8, Folder no number)
    - Misc. smaller series, undated (Box 8, Folder no number)
    - Misc. photos, undated (Box 8, Folder no number)
  - Subseries B: 5 x 7" snapshots
    Contains 5 x 7 snapshots of a wide array of subjects, including trips to Latin America, Cuba, India, and many regions of the United States. Also included are photos of a reading by actors Taylor Mead and Bill Rice, Indiana and others, an exhibit at the Museum of Contemporary Art in La Jolla, California, and photos of The Bishop's School in La Jolla, from which Andrew Cunanan graduated in 1987. Figures documented prominently include Bill Rice, Taylor Mead, and author William S. Burroughs.
    - Indiana posing with umbrella, undated (Box 9, Folder no number)
    - Black Lite Cocktail Room, Los Angeles, undated (Box 9, Folder no number)
    - Latin America and New York, undated (Box 9, Folder no number)
    - Reading/Performance: Bill Rice, Taylor Mead, Gary Indiana and others, undated (Box 9, Folder no number)
    - Unknown house nad pool, undated (Box 9, Folder no number)
    - Sepia photos: England, Latin America, New York, undated (Box 9, Folder no number)
    - Poker with Bill Rice and others, undated (Box 10, Folder no number)
    - Poker with Bill Rice and others, undated (Box 10, Folder no number)
    - Miami Beach, undated (Box 10, Folder no number)
    - William S. Burroughs, undated (Box 10, Folder no number)
    - Branson, Missouri, undated (Box 10, Folder no number)
    - Hotel room, undated (Box 10, Folder no number)
    - La Jolla, CA (inc. The Bishop's School, Museum of Contemporary Art), undated (Box 11, Folder no number)
    - Labeled photos (Vaginal Davis, Richard Hawkins, Bruce la Bruce, others), undated (Box 11, Folder no number)
    - California, undated (Box 11, Folder no number)
    - Rural house, undated (Box 11, Folder no number)
    - Store windows, undated (Box 11, Folder no number)
    - Minneapolis, undated (Box 12, Folder no number)
    - Small New York series, undated (Box 12, Folder no number)
    - Savannah, GA and South Carolina, undated (Box 12, Folder no number)
    - Fort Delaware, undated (Box 12, Folder no number)
    - Party, gallery, and people snapshots, undated (Box 13, Folder no number)
    - Cuba, undated (Box 13, Folder no number)
    - India, undated (Box 14, Folder no number)
    - California, undated (Box 15, Folder no number)
    - Misc. Smaller Series, undated (Box 15, Folder no number)
    - Misc. Photos, undated (Box 15, Folder no number)
  - Subseries C: 8.5 x 11" photos and photocollages
    Contains Indiana's 8.5 x 11 photo series, retaining his original order and organization. Major series include travel photos, nudes, cemetery photos, digital collage work by Indiana, and contact sheets from the film Bangkok Talkie and the play The Roman Polanski Story.
    - Binder 1: Cemetery, India, Collages, Rural, undated (Box 16, Folder no number)
    - Binder 2: Latin America, Nudes, Collages, Rural, undated (Box 17, Folder no number)
    - Binder 3: New York City, Collages, Nudes, undated (Box 18, Folder no number)
    - Binder 4: Collages, Latin America, undated (Box 18, Folder no number)
    - Binder 5: India, Burroughs, Text Photos, Nudes, Exhibition Photos, New York City, undated (Box 19, Folder no number)
    - Binder 6: Cemetery, Collages, Text Photos, Transparencies, undated (Box 20, Folder no number)
    - Binder 7: Nudes, Cemetery, India, New York City, Paris, Latin America, Rural, undated (Box 20, Folder no number)
    - Binder 8: Paris, Rural, New York City, Nudes, undated (Box 21, Folder no number)
    - Unsorted 8.5 x 11" photos, undated (Box 21, Folder no number)
    - [AWAITING SLEEVES; WILL BE:] Grouping of 8.5 x 11" photos, undated (Box 22, Folder no number, Box 28)
  - Subseries D: Photo series grouped or labeled by Indiana
    Contains photography of varying sizes maintained in individual groupings created and sometimes labeled by Indiana.
    - [Labeled:] "Bangkok Talkie" / a film shot on glass plates / Bangkok 1982-3 / W/ Marina Abromowicz + Ulay, 1982-1983 (Box 23, Folder no number)
    - [Labeled:] Contact Sheets / 'The Roman Polanski Story' / Performing Garage, 1981 (Box 23, Folder no number)
    - [Labeled:] Contact Sheets 1978-79, 1978-1979 (Box 23, Folder no number)
    - Promotional photos, undated (Box 23, Folder no number)
    - X-Mas Card 1996 (Box 23, Folder no number)
    - Photos from "Bill Rice's typescript w/ Photos 'Curse of the Dog People'", undated (Box 23, Folder no number)
  - Subseries E: Slides, Negatives, and Transparencies
    Consists of two boxes of photographic slides, retaining Indiana's organization. Also included are several photographic negatives and one 4 x 5" transparency.
    - Photographic slides, undated (Box 24, Folder no number)
    - Photographic slides (continued), undated (Box 25, Folder no number)
    - Photographic negatives and transparency, undated (Box 25, Folder no number)
  - Subseries F: Oversize photographic materials
    contains oversize photographic items, including photos bearing the copyright of Digne Meller Marcowicz which mainly relate to Werner Schroeter and German theater productions.
    - Digne Meller Marcovicz photo 1 (Das Katchen von Heilbronn), undated (Box 26, Folder 212)
    - Marcovicz photo 2 (Das Katchen von Heilbronn), undated (Box 26, Folder 213)
    - Marcovicz photo 3 (Lohengrin), undated (Box 26, Folder 214)
    - Marcovicz photo 4 (Miss Sara Sampson), undated (Box 26, Folder 215)
    - Marcovicz photo 5 (Miss Sara Sampson), undated (Box 26, Folder 216)
    - Marcovicz photo 6 (Miss Sara Sampson), undated (Box 26, Folder 217)
    - Marcovicz photo 7 (The Florentine Tragedy), undated (Box 26, Folder 218)
    - Marcovicz photo 8 (Neapolitanische Geschwister), undated (Box 26, Folder 219)
    - Marcovicz photo 9 (Neapolitanische Geschwister), undated (Box 26, Folder 220)
    - Marcovicz photo 10 (Palermo ober Wolfsburg), undated (Box 26, Folder 221)
    - Marcovicz photo 11 (Das Liebeskonzil), undated (Box 26, Folder 222)
    - Marcovicz photo 12 ("Frankfurt - Romerberg mit Justizia"), undated (Box 26, Folder 223)
    - Marcovicz photo 13 (Universitat Frankfurt / Horsaal VI / Kolakowski), undated (Box 26, Folder 224)
    - Marcovicz photo 14 (Frankfurt - Romer / Helmut Kohl), undated (Box 26, Folder 225)
    - Marcovicz photo 15 (Frankfurt - Romerberg - CDU Wahlveranstaltung), undated (Box 26, Folder 226)
    - Marcovicz photo 16 (Thomas Bernhard), undated (Box 26, Folder 227)
    - Marcovicz photo 17 (Werner Schroeter), undated (Box 26, Folder 228)
    - "Flocons d'Or" (photo by Roswitha Hecke), undated (Box 26, Folder 229)
    - Photo by Rodolfo Alcaraz, undated (Box 26, Folder 230)
    - Photo of two women, undated (Box 26, Folder 231)
    - Photo of father and son, undated (Box 26, Folder 232)
- Oversize Items
  Oversize items comprise posters for a 2004 speaking date and the plays Alligator Girls Go to College and The Roman Polanski Story, and several photographic works. Also included are galley proofs of White Trash Boulevard from the Manuscripts series, and a signed Patti Smith poster entitled "You Can't Say 'Fuck' in Radio Free America," removed from her personal correspondence with Indiana. A 2005 issue of Night has been removed from the Printed Materials series. An oversize poster for the 1980 Times Square Show, removed from the Flyers series, is located in the Mapcase.
  - White Trash Boulevard galley proofs, undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Times Square Show flyer, undated (Folder 9)
  - Night #52, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 161)
  - Signed poster: "You Can't Say 'Fuck' in Radio Free America" by Patti Smith, undated (Box 27, Folder 233)
  - The Roman Polanski Story poster, undated (Box 27, Folder 234)
  - Alligator Girls Go To College poster (5 copies), undated (Box 27, Folder 235)
  - Palmer Museum lecture poster, 2004 (Box 27, Folder 236)
  - Three large photographs (one is signed "Love, Lynne"), undated (Box 27, Folder 237)
  - Signed photo by Bill Rice: "'Dress Suits for Hire' for Gary", undated (Box 27, Folder 238)